THOMAS TARAB

CONTACT



+1.845.891.3977



ttarabbia@gmail.com



4411 Spicewood Springs Rd. Austin, TX 78759



In linkedin.com/thomastarabbia

SKILLS

- Client Needs Assessment
- Functional & Integration Architecture Development
- Complex Solution Sales
- **Executive Presentations**
- Sales and Pricing Strategy

EDUCATION

BSBA | INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS Thomas Edison State College '2014

LANGUAGES

- English
- French
- Czech

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems designer and Supply Chain solution architect. Highly skilled in managing the sales cycle from initial problem and scope mapping to workshops and roadmap development. Exceptional in leading and motivating multiple groups in complex enterprise sales. Implemented key processes to drive structure in sales teams growing 40%+ annually through acquisitions. Industry experience in cloud, telecomm, high-tech, and electronics supply chain. Effective communicator with strong attention to detail accustomed to working in a complex fast growing environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOLUTIONS CONSULTANT

E2OPEN LLC | Austin, TX | May 2019 - Present

- Personally drove revenue of \$1.1M in ARR (TCV >\$3M), \$2M of professional services, and \$5M of renewals in FY2020. Closed \$1.4M ARR in FQ1 2021.
- Develop and architect solutions in strategic accounts including building technical integration and functional strategies bridging across customer, logistics, and supplier facing silos.
- Managing a pipeline of \$11M by expanding customer relationships and prospects
- Perform hands on design work to prove solution capabilities to customers during the evaluation (Proof of Concept) process
- Feedback industry trends, bring up current or future gaps, and drive product roadmap and strategy to product management leaders
- Generate demand through intimate webinars and roundtables with handpicked attendees from key high-tech companies
- Prototyped and mocked up platform functionality using Python to drive product improvements and create better standards
- Assist sales-force by developing product sales strategies for account based pursuits
- Collaborate with Professional Services & Customer Success to ensure customer outcome alignment and streamlining processes
- Trained internal teams on supply chain and industry issues to drive improved discovery by the account teams
- Collaborate with Partner Network (Big 4 consulting) on go-to-market and account strategy

THOMAS TARABBIA

RECENT READS

- Fooled By Randomness; Taleb
- How to Win in a Winner-Take-All World; Irwin
- The Effortless Experience; Dixon, Toman, Delisi
- Storyworthy:Engage, Teach, and Persuade; Dicks
- How Adam Smith Can Change Your Life; Roberts
- But What If We're Wrong;
 Klosterman
- A Canticle for Liebowitz; Miller
- Deep Work; Newport

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED...

RFP/FIELD ENABLEMENT MANAGER

E2OPEN LLC | Austin, TX | June 2017 - May 2019

- Automated RFX development leading to 70% reduction in man-hours to respond - a typical month required submission of 20+ written responses
- Developed and managed prospect/customer facing content including solution slides, infrastructure, security, and Cloud Ops
- Aligned RFX responses and presentations to sales/solutions strategy
- Dove deep into codified and tribal knowledge to create sales/solution training materials and knowledge management system
- Simplified price and solution book structure
- Responsible for BDR's training on solutions, industry knowledge, and positioning across verticals
- Managed in-person and virtual training sessions along with video and audio editing and recording
- Planned and executed annual Sales Kickoff with 200+ attendees

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT REPRESENTATIVE

E2OPEN LLC | Austin, TX | March 2016 - June 2017

- Achieved consistent 125% of quota over multiple quarters by spending consistent time learning about customer stories and the business/solution landscape
- Penetrated Fortune 500 accounts with industry knowledge & known value drivers in cold calls, emails, referrals, and LinkedIn InMail
- Implemented strategic selling and prospecting across disparate organizations

LEAD DEVELOPMENT REPRESENTATIVE

ALCHEMY SYSTEMS | Austin, TX | March 2015 - March 2016

- Developed relationships by cold calling and marketing campaigns with prospects from the C-suite down to the associate level to garner engagement and solution sales activities
- Attended industry events, manning exhibition stands, and actively engaging with attendees to promote the brand through industry expertise

SALES REPRESENTATIVE

STORMHILL MEDIA | Austin, TX | Summer 2014

- Researched and solicited small businesses in need of website redesign or optimization
- Prospecting, whitespace development and sales support